All my friends and I come to exercise number 88 in this exercise, we are going to implement the adjacency
metrics and job we have learned enough about adjacency metrics.
Now let's implement this theory into the codes, so I need to like to simplify that.
We are what we are going to do in this exercise.
We are going to create a four arrows matrix and four columns metrics, and we are going to specify the
elements and the connection between these edges.
So here we need to create four four times four metrics.
Start from zero one two and three zero one two and three.
And then we need to create a connection between zero and one and one and zero.
So whenever you put one here, you need zero one.
You inverse it one zero.
There is a connection.
OK.
So this is presenting a graph of four four.
Vertices is here.
Zero one.
Sorry.
Two and three.
There is a connection between zero and one and one and zero because it is undirected graph, so zero
one one zero.
So we put one zero here.
I need to create a connection between zero and two.
So zero two, there is a connection and do zero.
There is a connection.
OK.
I need to create a connection between one and two.
So one is connected to two and two is connected to one.
So one two is connected and two one is connected
to zero connected.
OK.
And the connection between two and the three is connect.
Do and the city do is connected to three and the three connected to two.
OK.
And the rest is zero.
OK, I need to create an algorithm to create a program that allows for me to represent this matrix.
This graph into a matrix and this matrix should be works fine in this project.
OK, so let's just start implementing this exercise.
I want from you to post the video and start thinking about how to solve like this exercise.
I'm waiting for a solution in the comments below.
So let's create a new Java class here inside the source folder, and I will name it as adjacency
matrix.
And by the way, you can get all of these source codes that we have created before underneath every,
every lecture, every exercise that we it's specific to at our you can download it from the resource
folder from that link below that to me.
OK, so this is the adjacency matrix.
We start by creating it because it is depending on a matrix.
So we are going to create a two dimensional array.
So private Boolean.
I will call it as.
Because it is a Boolean.
Boolean metrics adjacency matrix that that accepts only one and two.
OK.
And it is two dimensional that there is a bully and a private bent.
Numbers of their diseases.
OK, now let's initialize the metrics at the first step, initialize
the metrics.
This is the first step I like to make comments in order to understand when you revised the code.
Understand everything.
So public adjacency matrix this constructor.
So when we create an adjacency matrix, we should specify in its parameter the number of vertices is
and the number of vertices is this number over.
This number of vertices is equal to number of vertices, and we specify adjacency matrix equal to new
Boolean Boolean matrix number of vertices and here number of places.
I make it exactly the same because there is an implied that by their logic, in adjacency matrix, it's
a squared matrix.
So if you create five Quiroz, you should create five columns because we have the same count the connection
we need.
If we have five or eight vertices, we are understanding the relation between five the five edges and
the five vertices is OK.
So five edges, we have possibility of twenty five.
If we have five vertices, we have possibility of 25 edges at MAX, so we create it at a square matrix.
This is a very important trick and may be asked in interviews and the examples now at the edges.
Public void and edge I will put and I and in j because the edge would contain STO, the destination
and the source.
So let me put it source or see that we have created in the previous video and this destination when
implementing that graph.
So adjacent metrics at index as C and destination equal to the rule and make the same connection between
the destination and the source.
OK,
true.
As I said to you, if there is a connection between zero and two, there is a connection between two
and zero.
OK.
This is very important in undirected graph.
I repeat to you in undirected graph in in direct to the graph, this is not applicable.
OK.
Maybe or maybe not.
There is a connection between source and destination and destination and source.
OK.
No third step is to remove edges if we need to remove the edges, so we specify the remove edge destination
and source again.
And I.
Or source and destination.
I need to remove the adjacency matrix source.
I would copy them from here and place them here and just put it false, and it will indicate zero for
it.
OK, no.
In order to print The Matrix, I need to get all of this Boolean adjacent metrics.
And since that this boolean so true, I need to put it and remove through and put it one and everything
else we have inside this matrix.
We should replace it with the zero.
So printing that graph or that to The Matrix is done by making a nested loop.
So I will create this structure and the metrics I will overload the public
string to string.
To string method
and this will be printing it.
So for that, I will create a string builder
as continuous string bowler.
So if you want to learn more about Java, please, you can enroll with into that into the complete Java
developer course for our on the same Udemy platform.
OK.
So there is a contact us.
We can send you a free Capote funeral with this Jeff, of course, equal to zero idol as the number
of diseases.
And I say plus then as a friend, we need to add and append addition at the end.
And here for this is the nested loop boolean j j of metrics a decent metrics for every element inside
this matrix.
Adjacent metrics make a Boolean case such that we need to print this.
Okay, so append this key.
This is J.
J.
If it is.
Drew then make it one.
Otherwise, it will be zero.
OK.
This is the meaning of this.
No.
Take shortcuts.
OK.
Plus space between them.
And here we go as the abend and
OK.
And here return and start to strike again.
So we are printing it now.
Let's test our test thing here and creating the code so public.
Static void main.
This is this game asks
so Graph
G equals the new graph of From the X.
So we have vertices for.
Number of vertices is equal to four.
So I will create a constructor.
OK, adjacency matrix, I would create adjacency adjacency matrix, sorry, I have missed that, we
have named it as adjacency matrix.
Now G Dot + + between zero and one.
This is the source, and this is the destination.
OK.
I was complicated.
I will create between zero and two.
Between one and two, between two and zero, it is the same here.
I know zero and two it will create two end zero.
But in order to check our program if it is working fine, OK?
And this is a city.
System that out to prevent
due to history.
OK, let's learn how.
Let's test our program here.
Sorry, I need to run this program.
Ron, and this is our metrics.
Let's see if it is true, this is our matrix.
This is our graph that we have created in the beginning of this video.
Zero, one, two and three.
We have transformed it to the adjacency matrix.
And this is the adjacency matrix.
So zero one one zero one zero one zero one one zero one and zero zero one zero.
Congratulations, guys.
We have implemented correctly the adjacency matrix in a graph in Java and C.
Now let's move to the adjacency less.